Guide to the Henry Foner Papers and Photographs TAM.254
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Henry Foner Papers and Photographs
1922-2013
1940-2004
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Foner, Henry
TAM.254
16 Linear Feet in 14 record cartons, 1 manuscript box, 1 flat box, and 2 folders in oversize flat boxes, 1 oversize folder in flat-file cabinet
70.2 Megabytes in 16 files
Henry Foner (1919- ) was president of the Joint Board, Fur, Leather and Machine Workers Union (FLM) and a social activist. After serving in World War II, Foner was appointed Welfare and Educational Director of the FLM; in 1961, he was elected union president. Foner worked on a wide range of progressive issues, from promoting civil rights to protesting the Vietnam War. After retiring in 1988, Foner taught labor history and wrote a column for the journal Jewish Currents. The records and photographs cover Foner's professional activities, familial relationships, musical interests, involvement with the Rapp-Coudert Committee and academic freedom, and other personal interests.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials donated by Henry Foner prior to 2001 and in batches since 2001; additional materials were found in the repository in 2014. The accession numbers associated with these gifts are 1950.122, 1950.257, 2001.151, 2001.206, NPA.2005.075, NPA.2005.224, NPA.2006.035, NPA.2006.060, NPA.2006.087, NPA.2007.015, 2011.070, 2014.026, and 2014.147.
Appraisal
Eight front pages of the FLM Joint Board's publication Tempo mounted as plaques were discarded in 2014.
Arrangement
This collection has been grouped into six series:
Missing Title
Series I: Family
Series II: Correspondence
Series III: Writings and Writings by Others
Subseries A: General
Subseries B: Rapp-Coudert Committee
Subseries C: Paul Robeson
Series IV: Subject Files
Series V: Addendum
Series VI: Photographs
Historical/Biographical Note
Henry J. Foner (1919- ), longtime activist leader of the Joint Board, Fur, Leather and Machine Workers Union (FLM), grew up in New York, in the Williamsburg section of Brooklyn. His father had a seltzer delivery route, and later owned a garage. In high school, Foner started playing saxophone with a band at hotels in the Catskills. He also started composing comic verses, played to the tunes of popular songs. By the late 1930s, Foner had acquired an interest in history and politics from his older brothers, Moe, Philip and Jack, and began developing the commitment to progressive activism that would shape his life. After graduating from City College with a degree in Business Administration in 1939, Foner organized "Student Caravans for America," which sent groups around the country to perform puppet shows promoting an anti-war message. The puppets were made by Pete Seeger. Foner's own group had its puppets and stage destroyed by a group of vandals in Bristol, Vermont and had to be rescued by the local sheriff.
In 1940, Foner's three brothers were all working at City College when the actions of the Joint Legislative Committee to Investigate the Educational System of the State of New York, known as the Rapp-Coudert Committee - investigating Communism in New York public schools and colleges, and employing tactics that later became a template for the House Un-American Activities Committee investigations - resulted in their suspension, along with fifty other employees of New York City Colleges.
At the time, Henry Foner, who had received his substitute-teaching license in stenography and typewriting, was teaching at Samuel J. Tilden High School in Brooklyn. He had already passed all parts of the regular teaching examination, but he was not granted that license because of an "insufficiently meritorious record" after he, too, had been questioned by the committee, and he initiated an appeal from that decision to the New York State Commissioner of Education. Meanwhile, together with two of his brothers, he helped form "The Foner Orchestra and their Suspended Swing" in mock homage to their experience. During the summer of 1941, they played at Arrowhead Lodge in Ellenville, New York, where the post of staff comic was filled by Sam Levenson, a friend of the family who, at that time, was teaching with Foner at Tilden High School.
In the summer of 1942, Foner was drafted into the Army and assigned to the 88th Infantry Division in Camp Gruber, Oklahoma, where he rose to the rank of warrant officer. After his division entered combat in Italy, he was awarded the Legion of Merit, the Italian Military Valor Cross, "for exceptionally meritorious conduct in the performance of outstanding services." Upon returning from military service in 1946, he resumed teaching, this time at Prospect Heights High School in Brooklyn, while awaiting the outcome of his appeal to the State Commissioner. During the summers of 1946, 1947, and 1948, he and his brother Jack were part of the orchestra at Arrowhead Lodge, which became the official resort of the Jefferson School of Social Science, whose faculty was made up largely of victims of the Rapp-Coudert Committee, joined by other scholars. During the summer of 1947, he met his wife, Lorraine Lieberman, and they were married in March 1948.
In 1947, together with Norman Franklin, Foner co-authored a musical, "Thursdays Till Nine" that was sponsored by the Department Store Employees Union and performed by its members -- the first labor musical since "Pins and Needles," written a decade earlier for the International Ladies' Garment Worker's Union by Harold Rome. Immediately after returning from his summer employment at Arrowhead Lodge in 1948, Foner was informed that his appeal to the State Commissioner had been denied and his substitute teacher license was withdrawn. At the time, his brother, Philip, had been writing what was to become a history of the fur and leather workers' union, and he introduced Foner to the leaders of the union, which led Foner's being hired as Educational and Welfare Director of the Joint Board Fur Dressers' and Dryers' Unions. In 1961, after the death of Joint Board President Sam Burt, Foner was elected president of the union and served in that capacity until his retirement in 1988. During his 27 years in the leadership of the Joint Board, he not only represented the union's members in contract negotiations in a union that covered workers in the fur, leather, and machine industries in the states of New York, New Jersey, Pennsylvania, Delaware, and West Virginia, but he helped involve that union in a wide range of social issues, including the struggle for civil rights, helping to mobilize other unions in opposition to the war in Vietnam and joining in the early efforts to achieve universal healthcare coverage. He also established and edited the union's newspaper, FLM Joint Board TEMPO, which, for ten successive years, won the first prize for "general excellence" in the competitions sponsored by the International Labor Press Association. In addition to his union work, Foner also served as a vice-chairman of the New York State Liberal Party, as chair of the party's Labor Committee, as a member of governor Mario Cuomo's Committee on labor practices and as a member of New York City Mayor John Lindsay's Committee of the Judiciary. After the fur industry was attacked by animal rights activists, Foner served on the board of Wildlife Legislative Fund of America and authored a weekly column, "Conservation, Legislation and You" for the trade newspaper, Fur Age Weekly.
After retiring from the union in 1988, Foner helped create the Fur Design Department at the Fashion Institute of technology (FIT) and served for two years as its chair. He also taught classes in labor history at the Harry Van Arsdale School for Labor Studies, the City College Center for Worker Education and the Brooklyn College Institute for Retirees in Pursuit of Education (IRPE), joined the Editorial Board of Jewish Currents magazine and for three years wrote its column, "It Happened in Israel." He was also vice-president of the Brooklyn Philharmonic Symphony Orchestra, treasurer (and later president) of the Paul Robeson Foundation, and a member of the Executive Committee of the New York Labor History Association, whose newsletter, Work History News, he continues to edit. In 2000, he privately published a booklet of his poems and songs, For Better or Verse. The same year, together with labor historian Rachel Bernstein and later joined by Evelyn Jones Rich, he helped found the website Labor Arts (www.laborarts.org) sponsored by the Shelley and Donald Rubin Foundation, the Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University, and 1199/SEIU's Bread and Roses cultural program.
Foner and his three brothers were all involved in issues involving labor and radical history. The twins, Philip and Jack, had distinguished careers as historians after their exit from City College in 1940 - Philip at Lincoln University in Pennsylvania and Jack at Colby College in Maine. Moe was executive secretary of Local 1199 during its dramatic organizational campaigns in the hospitals of New York City and beyond and later went on to found the Bread and Roses cultural program. In the next generation, Jack's son, Eric, has distinguished himself, as a professor of history at Columbia University and Moe's daughter, Nancy, is currently a professor of sociology at Hunter College. In 1985, the four brothers received the Tom Paine award from the Emergency Civil Liberties Committee for their actions in defense of civil right and civil liberties. Fourteen years later - in 1999 - they received the Distinguished Labor Communicators' Award from the Metro Labor Press Association. In 2003, Foner received a Lifetime Achievement Award from Jews for Radical and Economic Justice (JFREJ). His wife of 54 years, Lorraine Lieberman Foner, who had received a Special Baccalaureate Degree from Brooklyn College, worked as a social worker at Brookdale hospital in Brooklyn until her retirement in 1988, died of complications of a brain tumor.
Related Archival Materials
Philip Foner Papers (TAM 153)
Conference on Democracy in Education Records (TAM 221)
International Fur and Leather Workers' Union Records, 1913-1955. Catherwood Library Kheel Center, Cornell University (Collection Number: 5676)
Scope and Content Note
This collection is made up of the papers and photographs which have been donated by Henry Foner in numerous batches since 2001. The records and photographs cover Foner's professional activities, familial relationships, musical interests, involvement with the Rapp-Coudert Committee and academic freedom, and other personal interests.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Born-Digital Access Policies and Procedures
An access terminal for born-digital materials in the collection is available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Researchers may view an item's original container and/or carrier, but the physical carriers themselves are not available for use because of preservation concerns.
Working class -- United States.; Correspondence.; Sheet music.; Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York |x Political activity |x History |y 20th century.; Labor unions -- New York (State); New York (N.Y.).; Lyric writing (Popular music); Revues |v Scores.; Photographs.; Catskill Mountains Region (N.Y.) |x History.; Anti-communist movements -- United States -- 20th century; Labor leaders -- New York (State); Typescripts; Academic freedom -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Catskill Mountains Region (N.Y.) |x Social life and customs.; Transcripts.; City University of New York. City College; Rosenberg, Bernard, 1923-1996; Robeson, Paul, 1898-1976; Foner, Henry; Foner, Lorraine; Dorinson, Joseph, 1936-; Karr, Russell; Foner, Jack D.; Foner, Moe, 1915-; Foner, Philip Sheldon, 1910-1994; New York (State). Legislature. Joint Legislative Committee to Investigate the Educational System of the State of New York; Skinner, Byron Richard; Burman, Martin; Franklin, Norman L.; Buckser, Craig; Joint Board, Fur, Leather & Machine Workers Union
- Series I: Family
  Scope and Content Note
  Series I: Family, includes letters Foner wrote while in the U.S. Army; information about memorial tributes, writings, and other materials by and related to Foner's family; also includes Department of State, FBI and Military Intelligence reports on Foner, and other biographical materials.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Army Letters Written to His Family, 1942-1945 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Brothers in Dissent (Newsday Article), 1986 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Brooklyn College IRPE, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Cards and Poems, 1960-2000 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Cards-Birthday, Holiday, and Condolence, 1986-2000 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Foner, Abraham, 1955-1959 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Foner Brothers- Tom Paine Award, NECLC and Related Materials, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Foner, Diane, 1965-1990 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Foner, Diane - Letters, Poems, and Writings, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Foner, Diane - Memorial Booklet, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Foner, Diane - Memorial Tribute, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Foner, Diane - Condolence Letters and Memorial Book, 1989-1997 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Foner, Eric, 1969-1997 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Foner Family Correspondence, 1944-2000 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Foner, Henry - 50th Birthday Party, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Foner, Henry - 60th Birthday Party, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Foner, Henry - 85th Birthday Party, 2004 (Flat-file-folder 2, Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Foner, Henry - Awards, 1988-2004 (Box 1, Folder 17a)
  - Foner, Henry - CCNY Class of 1939 Reunion, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Foner, Henry - Correspondence with CIA and FBI, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Foner, Henry - Family Materials, 1944-1997 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Foner, Henry - FBI, Military Intelligence Materials, 1948-1976 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Foner, Henry - Military Record/Service Certificate, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Foner, Henry - Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Foner, Henry - Reminiscence Writings, Undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Foner, Henry - Resumes/Brief Biography, , 1998, 2002, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Foner, Henry - Retirement From FLM, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Foner, Jack and Thomas (includes memorial tributes), 2000 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Foner, Justin - Poems, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Foner, Laura and Elizabeth - Correspondence, 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Foner, Liza and Thomas, Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Foner, Liza - " The Artful Comments of Liza Foner", Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Foner, Liza - "Reflections on Art and Artists", 2003 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Foner, Lorraine - Letters of Condolence, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Foner, Lorraine - "Sweet Lorraine", 2002 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Foner, Lorraine - Memorial, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 10a)
  - Foner, Mary, 1956-1968 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Foner, Moe - "Concerning Moe Foner" by Henry Foner, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Foner, Moe - Miscellaneous Material, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Foner, Moe - Memorial, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Foner, Moe - Obituaries, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Foner, Moe - "Reminiscences" (1 of 6), 1989 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Foner, Moe - "Reminiscences" (2 of 6), 1989 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Foner, Moe - "Reminiscences" (3 of 6), 1989 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Foner, Moe - "Reminiscences" (4 of 6), 1989 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Foner, Moe - "Reminiscences" (5 of 6), 1989 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Foner, Moe - "Reminiscences" (6 of 6), 1989 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Foner Orchestra Stationery, Undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Foner, Philip S. - Articles and Essays, Undated, 1970, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Foner, Philip S. - Assorted Material, 1936, 1976-1994 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Foner, Philip S. - "Bibliography 1941-1994" NYLHA (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Foner, Philip S. - Biographical Materials, Undated, 1991, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Foner, Philip S. - Obituaries, 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Foner, Philip S. - "We Dare Be Free", 1983 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Foner, Rachel - Poems, Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Foner, Roslyn Held - Memorial, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - For Better or For Verse- Original Pages, Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - For Better or For Verse- Original Pictures, Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - For Better or For Verse - Responses to, 2000-2001 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Fountain Garage Mortgage Statements/Agreements, 1924-1972 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Fountain Garage Trust, 1954-1984 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Mountaindale Property, ca.1955-1968 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Mt. Lebanon Cemetery, 1928-1991 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Pittsburgh Foners, Undated, 1984-2000 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Pittsburgh Foners- Judith Cohen, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Pittsburgh Foners- Mayer and Sarah Menkin Foner, 1978-1980 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Pittsburgh Foners- Simon Foner and Family, 1977-1998 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Pittsburgh Foners- Rachel Foner Powell and Family, 1998-2000 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Pittsburgh Foners- Mary F. Rosenthal, 1991-2000 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Sheintel, Kimberly - Family Trees, Undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Series II: Correspondence
  Arranged chronologically.
  Series II: Correspondence, consists of Foner's letters to editors, incoming and outgoing letters related to political activities, including those detailing efforts to overturn the decision not to grant Foner a teaching license, as well as business conducted as union president.
  - Foner, Henry Correspondence, 1940-1949, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Foner, Henry Correspondence, 1960-1969 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Foner, Henry Correspondence, 1970-1979 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Foner, Henry Correspondence, 1980-1989 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Foner, Henry Correspondence, 1990-1992 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Foner, Henry Correspondence with Herbert Brown, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Foner, Henry Correspondence, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Foner, Henry Correspondence, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Foner, Henry Correspondence, 1995-1997 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Foner, Henry Correspondence, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Foner, Henry Correspondence, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Foner, Henry Correspondence, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Foner, Henry Correspondence, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Foner, Lorraine, illness: E-mails regarding, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Foner, Henry Correspondence, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Foner, Henry Correspondence, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Foner, Henry Correspondence, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Foner, Henry Correspondence, Undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Series III: Writings and Writings by Others, 70.2 Megabytes in 16 files
  Series III: Writings and Writings by Others, includes draft, typescript, and published versions of Foner's poems, radio scripts, theatrical sketches, speeches, and articles written for Jewish Currents, among others. It also includes handwritten and published musical scores to songs, some written with Norman Franklin, and audio recordings created by the Wagner Archives of Foner singing labor songs. Other individuals represented in the this series include Russell Karr, Martin W. Burman, Byron R. Skinner, Bernard Rosenberg, Craig Buckser, and Joseph Dorinson.
  - Songs, Undated, 1930-1949 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Army Poems, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Songs, with Norman Franklin, 1941-1946 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Thursdays 'till 9, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Tribute to Paul Robeson (Robeson Autograph), 1949 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Assorted Articles on Paul Robeson, Undated, 1949, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Music Scores, 1940-1949 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Poems and Songs, 1950-1969 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Eastside Story, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Oy Chelm, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Poems and Songs, 1970-1979 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Jewish Currents articles, 1971-1998 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Assorted published articles, 1974-2004 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Labor's Struggle for a Shorter Work Week, ca.1977 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Poems and Songs, 1980-1989 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Writings about Moe Foner, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Fur Age Weekly - "Conservation, Legislation & You" (1 of 2), 1989-1991 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Fur Age Weekly - "Conservation, Legislation & You" (2 of 2), 1992-1996 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Poems and Songs, 1990-2008; includes one CD from 2008 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Work History News, NYLHA (1 of 2), 1991-1999 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Work History News, NYLHA (2 of 2), 2000-2003 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Riverdale Speeches, 1992-1999 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - It Happened in Israel (Jewish Currents), 1993-1999 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Open Letter to Leonard Jeffries, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Fur Age Weekly Articles, 1993-1996 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Speeches at 92nd Street Y, 1993, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Jews for Racial and Economic Justice Conference Speech, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Jewish Currents Luncheon Speech, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Catskills Conference Speech and Information, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Older Women's League Meeting Speech, "Paul Robeson and the Women Who Helped Shaped His Life", 1998 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Long Island University Robeson Conference Speech, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Williamsburg Art and Historical Center Speech, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - For Better or Verse, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Paul Robeson Foundation Study Guide: A Century of Greatness, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Basketball Conference Speech, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Older Women's League Meeting Speech, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Play It Again Sam -- Henry Foner sings labor songs, March 19, 2008; TW_TAM_254_ER_1
  - Articles and Essays, Undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Assorted Songs by Henry Foner and Others, Undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Autobiographical Pieces, Undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Book Reviews, Undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Cammer, Harold: "A Belated Eulogy", Undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - In This Corner: Columns by Bill Mardo Edited by Henry and Lorraine Foner, Undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Labor's Struggle for a Shorter Work Week parts 1-3, ca.1977 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - My Fair Chelm, Undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Poems and Songs, Undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Poems from Independent Weekly Review, Undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Radio Scripts, Undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Songs for Local 1199, Hospital Workers, Undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - From the Rebbe's Court by Isaac Ewen, 1922, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Writings of Norman Franklin and Henry Foner, 1940-1999 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Dubois, W. E. B.: Pan Africa, 1947-1948 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Cammer, Harold, "The Nixon Supreme Court and Labor", 1976 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - The Experience of the International Fur and Leather Workers Union in the McCarthy Era, by Russell Karr, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Political Song Performance Styles of the Old and New Left, by Martin W. Burman (1 of 2), 1978 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Political Song Performance Styles of the Old and New Left, by Martin W. Burman (2 of 2), 1978 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - The Double V: the Impact of WWII on Black America, by Byron R. Skinner (1 of 2), 1978 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - The Double V: the Impact of WWII on Black America, by Byron R. Skinner (2 of 2), 1978 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - An Examination of the Development of the First Accredited Labor College in the US, by Bernard Rosenberg, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 22)